<help>
  <![CDATA[
'************************************************************************
' MC_Identify help.xml
'-----------------------------------------------------------------------

'------------------------------------------------------------------------
]]>
  
<ref id="AutoField">
  <ap>None.</ap>
  <h>
    This important action identifies red HCFA-1500 or red UB04 forms.<br/><br/>
    The action must be placed after a rule's <scr>SetMaxTolerantDistance, SetFormType, ReadDCOSetup,</scr> and <scr>SetWritePosFile</scr> actions (see the example below).
    <e>
      <scr>SetMaxTolerantDistance(60)</scr><br/>
      <scr>SetFormType(0)</scr><br/>
      <scr>ReadDCOSetup(HCFA.xml,POS 1052)</scr><br/>
      <b>AutoField()</b>      
    </e>
  </h>
  <lvl>Page level.</lvl>
  <ret>
    <b>False</b> if the action is not applied at the Page level; otherwise, <b>True.</b>
  </ret>
</ref>

<ref id="FindFields">
    <ap>None.</ap>
    <h>
      This action sets up a Data file (.xml) for the current page,
      and supplies the Data file with field position information.<br/><br/>

      Typically, this action is part of a Medical Claims <scr>ID_PageFix</scr> rule.
      <e>
        <scr>SetMaxTolerantDistance(60)</scr>
        <br/>
        <scr>SetFormType(0)</scr>
        <br/>
        <scr>ReadDCOSetup(HCFA.xml, POS1052)</scr>
        <br/>
        <b>FindFields()</b>
      </e>
    </h>
    <lvl>Page level only.</lvl>
    <ret>
      <b>False</b> if rule with this action is not bound to a Page object of the Document Hierarchy,
      or if a source page represented by the Page object is unavailable. Otherwise, returns <b>True.</b>
    </ret>
  </ref>

<ref id="SetMaxTolerantDistance">
    <ap>
      The Maximum Tolerant Distance - an <i>Integer</i>from 1 (Lowest Tolerance) to 100 (Highest Tolerance).
    </ap>
    <h>
      This action sets the tolerance level that <b>AutoField</b> will use to match HCFA-1500 or red UB04 forms
      (depending on the form specified using the <b>SetFormType</b>action).
      <e>
        <b>SetMaxTolerantDistance(60)</b>
        <br/>
        <scr>SetFormType(0)</scr>
        <br/>
        <scr>ReadDCOSetup(HCFA.xml, POS1052)</scr>
        <br/>
        <scr>AutoField()</scr>
      </e>
    </h>
    <lvl>All.</lvl>
    <ret>
      <b>False</b> if the parameter is not an <i>Integer</i>between 1 and 100. Otherwise, <b>True.</b>
    </ret>
  </ref>

<ref id="SetFormType">
  <ap>
    <i>String</i>value indicating the Form Type:<br/>
    For HCFA-1500 or CMS-1500 use: "0" or "hcfa" <br/>
    For UB-04 use: "2" or "ub04".
  </ap>  
  <h>
    This action sets the Form Type value that will be used by <b>Autofield.</b>
    <e>
      <scr>SetMaxTolerantDistance(60)</scr><br/>
      <b>SetFormType(0)</b><br/>
      <scr>ReadDCOSetup(HCFA.xml, POS1052)</scr><br/>
      <scr>SetWritePosFile(True)</scr><br/>
      <scr>AutoField()</scr>
    </e>
  </h>
  <lvl>All.</lvl>
  <ret>
    <b>False</b> if the parameter is invalid. Otherwise, <b>True.</b>
  </ret>
</ref>

<ref id="ReadDCOSetup">
    <ap>
      A comma-separated <i>String</i> value made up a smart parameter that designates the Document Hierarchy's file
      name, followed by a Variable Name that indicates the position of the fingerprint. Typically, the file's name
      is the Application ID with an .xml extension; "HCFA.xml", for example, is the name of
      the <i>HCFA</i> application's Document Hierarchy file. "Pos1052" specifies a previously assembled
      HCFA-1500 fingerprint (in this case) with details of the form's Field IDs, locations and data types.
      For use with the Application Service the syntax of the first parameter changes to include the
      SmartParameter that will point to the setup dco, i.e. '@APPPATH(setupdco)' instead of 'HCFA.xml'.
    </ap>
    <h>
      <e>
        <b>ReadDCOSetup(HCFA.xml,Pos1052)</b><br/><br/>
        or for use with the Application Manager with the @APPPATH SmartParameter to locate the setup dco:<br/><br/>
        <b>ReadDCOSetup(@APPPATH(setupdco),Pos1052)</b><br/><br/>
        Note that this action is used with almost every other <b>MC_Identify</b> action.
      </e>
    </h>
    <lvl>All, but usually the Batch level.</lvl>
    <ret>
      <b>False</b> if the Document Hierarchy file is not found. Otherwise, <b>True.</b>
    </ret>
  </ref>
  <ref id="ReadPageSetup">
    <ap>
      1) A smart parameter enabled argument that designates the Document Hierarchy's file name and path.
      2) The fingerprint position variable name, usually "Pos" followed by the id of the fingerprint desired. 
      3) The Page type of the page to ID. Typically "PClaim" or "IClaim".
    </ap>
    <h>
      <e>
        <b>ReadPageSetup(@APPPATH(setupdco),Pos1059,PClaim)</b><br/><br/>
        Note that this action is used with almost every other <b>MC_Identify</b> action.
      </e>
    </h>
    <lvl>All.</lvl>
    <ret>
      <b>False</b> if the Document Hierarchy file is not found. Otherwise, <b>True.</b>
    </ret>
  </ref>
</help>
